Here’s The Problem...
Most entrepreneurs and
professionals are still doing
tasks every week that don’t
actually need them.
They’re stuck inside a mental loop
that says, “It’ll be faster if I
just do it myself.”
But it’s never faster in
the long run.
Repetitive work quietly drains
focus, decision-making energy, and
creativity.
Every time you retype the same
email, schedule the same meeting,
or copy-paste the same data,
you’re burning mental fuel that
could be spent on real progress.
Tony often says, “You can’t grow
if you’re doing what
keeps you small.”
Automation isn’t about
replacing effort.
It’s about reclaiming energy for
the work that actually moves your
business forward.
Here’s the Shift...
AI is no longer just a tool for
tech experts.
It’s your personal operations
assistant.
It can find the repetitive tasks
that are slowing you down,
organize them, and even recommend
what to automate first.
Once you see how much of your week
is filled with repeat work, you’ll
start to notice how much of your
potential has been
trapped inside it.
So Here’s Your Hack
We’re going to build a 3-step
AI-powered Automation Audit that
reveals where you’re wasting time
and how to reclaim it.
This process helps you:
Identify hidden bottlenecks that
drain hours weekly.
Classify tasks by automation
potential.
Build your first “AI Task Stack”.
A list of automations that will
save you time every single week.
Step 1 – Create Your Task Inventory
Open ChatGPT and paste this prompt:
“I want to find the top 3 tasks I
should automate.
I’ll list everything I do in a
typical week.
Please organize each task by
category (Admin, Communication,
Creative, Strategy) and estimate
how much time it consumes weekly.”
Example categories AI might create:
Admin (scheduling, invoices, file
organization)
Communication (emails, follow-ups,
meeting prep)
Creative (content creation,
brainstorming)
Strategy (planning, reporting,
reviewing metrics)
By seeing your tasks laid out,
you’ll notice how much of your
week is spent maintaining instead
of creating.
Step 2 – Find What’s Ripe for
Automation
Now paste this prompt:
“Based on my task list, identify
which items could be automated
with AI tools or workflows.
For each, suggest one possible
tool or system that could
handle it.”
Example:
Scheduling meetings → Automate
with Calendly or Motion.
Summarizing notes → Automate with
Fathom or Fireflies.
Rewriting posts → Automate with
ChatGPT or Jasper.
Pro Tip: Ask,
“Rank these automation
opportunities from easiest to
implement to highest impact.”
That way, you start with quick
wins that save you time
immediately.
Step 3 – Build Your “AI Task Stack”
Once you’ve got your list, say:
“Turn these automation
opportunities into a simple table
with three columns: Task, Tool,
and Time Saved per Week.”
You’ll now have a personal
Automation Dashboard.
Your roadmap to reclaim hours
every week.
Example output:
That’s 6 hours back this week and
every week after.
Real-World Example
Before AI:
Alex, a business coach, spent 10+
hours each week scheduling calls,
writing recap notes, and drafting
client updates.
His calendar looked full, but his
creativity was fried.
After AI:
He ran the Automation Audit and
realized 70% of those tasks could
be handled automatically.
Now, his week starts with clarity,
his follow-ups happen without
fail, and his creativity is back
where it belongs — serving
clients, not chasing admin tasks.
Mistake to Avoid
Don’t try to automate
everything at once.
Start small, automate one system,
test it, then layer the next.
You want evolution, not chaos.
Action Step
Make your list right now.
Drop your top 10 recurring tasks
into ChatGPT and run the
prompts above.
Circle the three that will save
you the most time or mental energy.
That’s your Automation Starter
Stack for this week.
💡 AI Amplifier Insight
Prompt:
“Analyze my weekly task list and
identify which 3 tasks would save
me the most time, energy, and
focus if automated.
Rank them by impact and ease of
implementation.”
This single exercise often gives
people back 3–5 hours a week… and
an enormous sense of peace.